<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 08:29:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Momentum</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/momentum/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Almost there&amp;rdquo;; sometimes these are the words of comfort I need to hear and sometimes they make want to attack the utterer. Being a runner and hiker means I get to hear them a lot more often than I want to. I love the intent behind them, they mean well. When I&amp;rsquo;m near the finish line, I welcome all variations of &amp;ldquo;Almost there&amp;rdquo; because its true, I can see the finish line and any form of discomfort I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing is bound to be over soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can run a marathon, you can do anything</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 07:02:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</guid>
      <description>I came up with the title of this post when I was at the peak of runner&amp;rsquo;s high that is after running a full marathon last weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be grateful if it inspires you but this its a note to self when I&amp;rsquo;ll need the reminder. This is not the first time I ran a marathon but its the first time I felt good. Yes, you read that right, I felt good even while running up a heart attack hill, I felt good on mile 23, I felt good as I finished and I felt especially good when I was functional again in 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</guid>
      <description>Every runner who is a also a writer writes their running story at some point. Its about time I wrote mine. I run at least 21 miles a week and have been consistently doing so for 4 years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t participate in every race there is, I&amp;rsquo;m far from a sub 2 hour half marathon, on many mornings its a struggle to get up and run. Despite all the struggles, I&amp;rsquo;m a consistent runner and sometimes a marathoner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Over my relatively short career as a Software Engineer I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize the importance of documentation. No one uses a feature they haven&amp;rsquo;t heard or read about. Compared to hours spent reading and debugging code, documentation may sound trivial but it makes a big difference for customers as well as team knowledge sharing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve subconsiously known this for a while, its why I started amazife blog as a College Freshman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Imaculate Mosha</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 08:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>📜 I spend most of my waking hours engineering software, running, writing and thinking about self-improvement. I&amp;rsquo;m currently based in Washington 🇺🇸 though I grew up in 🇹🇿 and studied in 🇿🇦 where I graduated with Electrical and Computer Engineering degree from the University of CapeTown. Welcome to my internet home!
👩‍💻 I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on your favorite Word Processor, Microsoft Word. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on both Backend and Frontend projects, more about that on my resume.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>