<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>resolutions on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/tags/resolutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in resolutions on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/tags/resolutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2023/</guid>
      <description>My reflection of 2023 is clouded with a less than ideal Q4 but I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to give it a fair trial. Its that time of the year so as tradition detects I&amp;rsquo;ll join the rest of humanity to look back and plan forward. With a slightly different format this time, lets dive in:
Highlights&amp;nbsp;¶Success on my first major fundraising project for Arthtitis. Started a profitable business. PR-ed on the 50K and 50 miler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolve</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/resolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:32:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/resolve/</guid>
      <description>This post was supposed to be about tips to crush New Years Resolutions. I wanted to share pointers like one of those people who have life figured out. It took less than 2 weeks to be reminded of my own fragility, impermanence and imperfection. Inspite of marginal success I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past, I&amp;rsquo;m still a work in progress, we all are. If you want tips on making and actualizing your resolutions, Google Is Your Friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2021/</guid>
      <description>I entered 2021 with lists and plans but life had plans of its own. I lost a loved one and everything changed. I&amp;rsquo;m still processing grief but if there is anything it has taught me is how short life is, how fragile, how impermanent. So, instead of chasing meaningless listicles, I chose to live and do more of what makes me happy. I ended up missing a few boxes and that&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
