<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>running on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/tags/running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in running on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/tags/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Training through the rut</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</guid>
      <description>Stick to the plan, trust the process, do it long enough and you&amp;rsquo;ll reach your goal, finish the race, get that medal or whatever tickles your fancy. Most times that works, we put in the work, celebrate, sign up for the next challenge and do it all over again. Its all fun and games until its not. Sure, you have the discipline to follow through with the plan but what if your heart is simply not in it anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Race</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday November 13th 2021, I woke up at 5:00 am, I did some prep, read for a bit before starting my almost 20 mile bike ride to Grand Ridge Park, Issaquah. I arrived just in time to get my bib and run my first ever trail race, the Grand Ridge Half Marathon. Despite all my doubts and fears,the run went pretty well, 3 hours 18 minutes kind of flew by before I reached the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endurance</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I could go on forever&amp;rdquo; is not something I ever imagined I&amp;rsquo;d say after running 14+ miles with over 4000ft thousands of elevation gain, but here we are. By ultra standards that is a piece of cake but I imagine the feeling is shared by all endurance athletes. Although this post was inspired by a run, it is not another running post; its about endurance. Before we get to that, gather around for a little bit of story time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life lessons from the trail</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</guid>
      <description>So I picked up a new sport recently and as you may expect, it involves running. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running up mountains and I have to admit I&amp;rsquo;ve been having too much fun with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fond of both running and mountains. They both present opportunities for challenges, scenery, connection and of course endorphins. Considering the effort needed to run uphill, it just made sense to run on the road and hike mountains at a leisurely pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</guid>
      <description>Every runner who is a also a writer writes their running story at some point. Its about time I wrote mine. I run at least 21 miles a week and have been consistently doing so for 4 years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t participate in every race there is, I&amp;rsquo;m far from a sub 2 hour half marathon, on many mornings its a struggle to get up and run. Despite all the struggles, I&amp;rsquo;m a consistent runner and sometimes a marathoner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
