<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>running on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/tags/running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in running on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/tags/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fittest</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/fittest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/fittest/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Geranimo on Unsplash
A lot of wake up calls happen at the doctor&amp;rsquo;s offce. All too often we hear about how bad news changed the trajectory of one&amp;rsquo;s life: death, terminal illness, cautionary test results you name it. This call is ussually followed by a resolve to live healthier lives, likely active but definitely fuller lives. I recently had one such call, except my doctor didn&amp;rsquo;t deliver bad news, nor did they bring particularly good news, they simply confirmed that everything was fine, there was nothing wrong in any of the standard annual exams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About that run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/warrior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 20:17:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/warrior/</guid>
      <description>Its been a while since I wrote about running, lets change that. A few months ago, I was running through never-ending flares, jumping from one medical appointment to the next and crying my way to acceptance. You know, typical rock-bottom, end of the world vibes. Four months later I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that the world infact did not end, life moved and I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Lets recap, I spent a good chunk of last year finding and pushing my limits, averaging one ultra a month, with crazy adventures sprinkled in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving on</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 15:28:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/chapter/</guid>
      <description>Most days that start with a run are good days. A 10 mile run gives just me enough endorphins to get me through the day and just enough fatigue to calm any anxiety, the world feels light and everything makes sense. Irrespective of how unpleasant the runs feels, I&amp;rsquo;m generally a pleasant person to be around afterwards. For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve trusted myself to be pleasant, not so much lately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/stillrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/stillrun/</guid>
      <description>How did I get here? By here I mean practically immobile in the passenger seat of a blue Subaru meandering through a private ranch with 3 folks who until this morning were complete strangers. So much to unpack here: immobile, private ranch, 3 strangers &amp;hellip; I assure you I wasn&amp;rsquo;t kidnapped. No, everything that led me to this point was mostly my own doing. These kind strangers were driving me back to the start line of a race I almost finished but didn&amp;rsquo;t because I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the last cutoff, I had ran 95% of the race course that traversed a private ranch, 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trail Year</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trail-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 20:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trail-year/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I did my first trail run and wrote my first trail inspired post. Little did I know of the adventures that were about to unfold. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve not only ran my longest distance in one day (50 miles), I&amp;rsquo;ve also grown comfortable running ultras. I think that&amp;rsquo;s wild considering that the half marathon used to be my stretch distance. On reflecting on the wild year, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some lessons I learnt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/years/</guid>
      <description>I get lots of ideas while running or thinking about running so its inevitable that my writing will have something to do with running. Being a card carrying member of the back-of-the-pack club comes with perpertual struggle to reconcile where you are and where you ought to be. It has been anever ending battle for a while but I eventually came to not only accept but also embrace slowness. Here is why:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training through the rut</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</guid>
      <description>Stick to the plan, trust the process, do it long enough and you&amp;rsquo;ll reach your goal, finish the race, get that medal or whatever tickles your fancy. Most times that works, we put in the work, celebrate, sign up for the next challenge and do it all over again. Its all fun and games until its not. Sure, you have the discipline to follow through with the plan but what if your heart is simply not in it anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Race</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday November 13th 2021, I woke up at 5:00 am, I did some prep, read for a bit before starting my almost 20 mile bike ride to Grand Ridge Park, Issaquah. I arrived just in time to get my bib and run my first ever trail race, the Grand Ridge Half Marathon. Despite all my doubts and fears,the run went pretty well, 3 hours 18 minutes kind of flew by before I reached the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endurance</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I could go on forever&amp;rdquo; is not something I ever imagined I&amp;rsquo;d say after running 14+ miles with over 4000ft thousands of elevation gain, but here we are. By ultra standards that is a piece of cake but I imagine the feeling is shared by all endurance athletes. Although this post was inspired by a run, it is not another running post; its about endurance. Before we get to that, gather around for a little bit of story time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life lessons from the trail</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</guid>
      <description>So I picked up a new sport recently and as you may expect, it involves running. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running up mountains and I have to admit I&amp;rsquo;ve been having too much fun with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fond of both running and mountains. They both present opportunities for challenges, scenery, connection and of course endorphins. Considering the effort needed to run uphill, it just made sense to run on the road and hike mountains at a leisurely pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</guid>
      <description>Every runner who is a also a writer writes their running story at some point. Its about time I wrote mine. I run at least 21 miles a week and have been consistently doing so for 4 years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t participate in every race there is, I&amp;rsquo;m far from a sub 2 hour half marathon, on many mornings its a struggle to get up and run. Despite all the struggles, I&amp;rsquo;m a consistent runner and sometimes a marathoner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
