<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>introvert on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/tags/introvert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in introvert on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 07:00:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/tags/introvert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The observer</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/observer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 07:00:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/observer/</guid>
      <description>It was then that I realized that even though we frequented the same venues and did similar things, our experiences could not be further apart.
Photo by Tengyart on Unsplash
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell exactly when this happened or what triggered it; it could have been a suprising text from a friend, unexpected news or casual socialization. There has been so many similar incidences where my assumptions about the world were challenged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nakia</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/alone/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself thinking a lot about Nakia lately, thanks to free stickers I got at a work event. Of all the options, I naturally gravitated to the strong female characters. Shuri and Okoye were easy picks since I aspire to be smart as the former and as strong as the latter, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t so sure about Nakia.
There is obvious merit to her character; in addition to saving Wakanda on multiple occasions, she is constantly striving it to help the rest of the world that is largely neglected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Walker</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/walker/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across this video of a penguin, call him Walker, committing suicide by running away from it all; the colony, the ocean, sustenance and everything that is essential for survival. On the surface, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, penguins are among the social creatures on earth. If nothing else, he should have wanted to stay in the colony. We can&amp;rsquo;t know for sure what was happening in his mind but we can make educated guesses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
