<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>story on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/tags/story/</link>
    <description>Recent content in story on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 07:02:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/tags/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You can run a marathon, you can do anything</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 07:02:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</guid>
      <description>I came up with the title of this post when I was at the peak of runner&amp;rsquo;s high that is after running a full marathon last weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be grateful if it inspires you but this its a note to self when I&amp;rsquo;ll need the reminder. This is not the first time I ran a marathon but its the first time I felt good. Yes, you read that right, I felt good even while running up a heart attack hill, I felt good on mile 23, I felt good as I finished and I felt especially good when I was functional again in 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Over my relatively short career as a Software Engineer I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize the importance of documentation. No one uses a feature they haven&amp;rsquo;t heard or read about. Compared to hours spent reading and debugging code, documentation may sound trivial but it makes a big difference for customers as well as team knowledge sharing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve subconsiously known this for a while, its why I started amazife blog as a College Freshman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
