<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</title>
    <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Imaculate&#39;s Internet home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 18:48:52 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://imaculate.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fulfilled</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/fulfillment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 18:48:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/fulfillment/</guid>
      <description>There comes a time in a one&amp;rsquo;s life when existential questions grow too loud to ignore. One that has been on my mind lately is fulfillment. It has been haunting me to the extent I thought online retailers were after me, throwing the word around like confetti; &amp;lsquo;Your order is fulfilled&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;[X] fulfillment center&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fulfill this&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fulfill that&amp;rsquo;. Sure, getting my package feels good but is it fulfilling? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release your wiggle</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 08:35:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/control/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash
I often get asked how I come up with my articles, if at all there is a formula behind this self-inflicted obligation to overshare what I overthink. Well, yes, its more of a process. At the end of the week, ussually on a long run or bike ride, I like to do a post-mortem reflecting on events of the week. Anything that repeatedly stands out makes it to this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolve</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/resolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:32:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/resolve/</guid>
      <description>This post was supposed to be about tips to crush New Years Resolutions. I wanted to share pointers like one of those people who have life figured out. It took less than 2 weeks to be reminded of my own fragility, impermanence and imperfection. Inspite of marginal success I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past, I&amp;rsquo;m still a work in progress, we all are. If you want tips on making and actualizing your resolutions, Google Is Your Friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2022/</guid>
      <description>Tis the season so lets talk about New Years; Photo by Cristian Escobar on Unsplash
I love the freshness and enthusiasism that comes with the calendar flip. Clouded by December merryments, we naively give ourselves permission to ignore logic and dream audaciously. I love the universality of it all; we may not celebrate the same deities but we atleast recognize the dawning of a new year. As a result, we get to collectively participate in the same ritual of looking back and plotting forward; speaking the same language of gratitude and resolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Life</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/good-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/good-day/</guid>
      <description>Every day should be a good day. People fool themselves that they&amp;rsquo;ll be here forever.
-Stephen A. Schwarzman
Saturday December 10th 2022 was a good day, of course there was a run involved. For the first time ever I ran a whole ultra on a whim and ended up running my fastest 50k to date. I say on a whim because I committed to running it at 4 am that morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving on</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 15:28:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/chapter/</guid>
      <description>Most days that start with a run are good days. A 10 mile run gives just me enough endorphins to get me through the day and just enough fatigue to calm any anxiety, the world feels light and everything makes sense. Irrespective of how unpleasant the runs feels, I&amp;rsquo;m generally a pleasant person to be around afterwards. For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve trusted myself to be pleasant, not so much lately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Walker</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/walker/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across this video of a penguin, call him Walker, committing suicide by running away from it all; the colony, the ocean, sustenance and everything that is essential for survival. On the surface, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, penguins are among the social creatures on earth. If nothing else, he should have wanted to stay in the colony. We can&amp;rsquo;t know for sure what was happening in his mind but we can make educated guesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S.O.S</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/sos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/sos/</guid>
      <description>When I first heard of the term SOS run from my run club, I thought it was a type of a fast run powered by adrenaline with some sort of simulated danger like sprinters in bear costume. As wild as my imagination was, I was partly right, a SOS run is indeed fast but there are no bears or costumes involved at least not planned. So what exactly is an SOS run?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/stillrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/stillrun/</guid>
      <description>How did I get here? By here I mean practically immobile in the passenger seat of a blue Subaru meandering through a private ranch with 3 folks who until this morning were complete strangers. So much to unpack here: immobile, private ranch, 3 strangers &amp;hellip; I assure you I wasn&amp;rsquo;t kidnapped. No, everything that led me to this point was mostly my own doing. These kind strangers were driving me back to the start line of a race I almost finished but didn&amp;rsquo;t because I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the last cutoff, I had ran 95% of the race course that traversed a private ranch, 28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trail Year</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trail-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 20:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trail-year/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I did my first trail run and wrote my first trail inspired post. Little did I know of the adventures that were about to unfold. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve not only ran my longest distance in one day (50 miles), I&amp;rsquo;ve also grown comfortable running ultras. I think that&amp;rsquo;s wild considering that the half marathon used to be my stretch distance. On reflecting on the wild year, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some lessons I learnt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/years/</guid>
      <description>I get lots of ideas while running or thinking about running so its inevitable that my writing will have something to do with running. Being a card carrying member of the back-of-the-pack club comes with perpertual struggle to reconcile where you are and where you ought to be. It has been anever ending battle for a while but I eventually came to not only accept but also embrace slowness. Here is why:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training through the rut</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/rut/</guid>
      <description>Stick to the plan, trust the process, do it long enough and you&amp;rsquo;ll reach your goal, finish the race, get that medal or whatever tickles your fancy. Most times that works, we put in the work, celebrate, sign up for the next challenge and do it all over again. Its all fun and games until its not. Sure, you have the discipline to follow through with the plan but what if your heart is simply not in it anymore?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on the pandemic</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 18:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Its official, after 2 years of unprecedented times, we are back to precedented times (almost). We are once again commuting to the office on a regular basis, flying and dining hassle-free, making social plans and interacting IRL without the overarching fear of droplets. If this were an apocalyptic movie, we&amp;rsquo;d be the lucky few who made it to the &amp;ldquo;happily ever after&amp;rdquo;. Sure, life is moving on; If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a happy ending, recall when you were self-isolating, consuming nothing but horror images and breaking news, craving hugs and better days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/2021/</guid>
      <description>I entered 2021 with lists and plans but life had plans of its own. I lost a loved one and everything changed. I&amp;rsquo;m still processing grief but if there is anything it has taught me is how short life is, how fragile, how impermanent. So, instead of chasing meaningless listicles, I chose to live and do more of what makes me happy. I ended up missing a few boxes and that&amp;rsquo;s okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Race</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-race/</guid>
      <description>On Saturday November 13th 2021, I woke up at 5:00 am, I did some prep, read for a bit before starting my almost 20 mile bike ride to Grand Ridge Park, Issaquah. I arrived just in time to get my bib and run my first ever trail race, the Grand Ridge Half Marathon. Despite all my doubts and fears,the run went pretty well, 3 hours 18 minutes kind of flew by before I reached the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Runner</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/slow-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/slow-runner/</guid>
      <description>10mintes 51 seconds, that&amp;rsquo;s the fastest I can run a mile, emphasis on fastest. The stars have to align for this to happen, I&amp;rsquo;d have to run on a flat surface, with good weather, fresh legs, sufficient training and of course I&amp;rsquo;d have to push really hard. In the same time, the elite marathoner Eliud Kipchoge runs twice the distance and then some. If I were to run alongside him, I&amp;rsquo;d look like Brittany while he flies ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#goals</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 08:18:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/goals/</guid>
      <description>I have this pebble that says &amp;ldquo;If you all can do is crawl, start crawling&amp;rdquo;. It has sentimental value, not just for the quote but it also reminds me of my state of my mind at the time I acquired it. Few weeks ago, I was in a small Norwegian town of Poulsbo where I had just finished a half marathon, high on endorphins, low in certainity. I had goals for the next few months that would stretch me way beyond my comfort zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/detour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 10:26:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/detour/</guid>
      <description>Fun fact about me, I have terrible sense of direction. Whenever I go someplace new, I budget for at least 15 minutes of getting lost. It happens so often that getting it right the first feels unnatural. A few highlights include the time I lost the bike trail and ended up biking on the highway (!!Do not try this at home!!), the one time I got lost kayaking on a lake (yes, that is possible), the time I spent finding my way in Osaka which was 100% of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endurance</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/endurance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I could go on forever&amp;rdquo; is not something I ever imagined I&amp;rsquo;d say after running 14+ miles with over 4000ft thousands of elevation gain, but here we are. By ultra standards that is a piece of cake but I imagine the feeling is shared by all endurance athletes. Although this post was inspired by a run, it is not another running post; its about endurance. Before we get to that, gather around for a little bit of story time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life lessons from the trail</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/trails/</guid>
      <description>So I picked up a new sport recently and as you may expect, it involves running. I&amp;rsquo;ve been running up mountains and I have to admit I&amp;rsquo;ve been having too much fun with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fond of both running and mountains. They both present opportunities for challenges, scenery, connection and of course endorphins. Considering the effort needed to run uphill, it just made sense to run on the road and hike mountains at a leisurely pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/change/</guid>
      <description>Quick question: How do you get your rice? No, rice is not a codeword for anything sketchy. I know its an odd question but bare with me for a second. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an answer to that question at the moment but not too long ago I had very detailed answers; I could point you to the closest grocery store with the best deals on long-grain rice, the exact aisle and the best time to shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breathe</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/breathe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 06:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/breathe/</guid>
      <description>Trigger Warning: grief, death
Inhale, exhale, Inhale, Exhale .. a dozen times a minute and thats enough to keep you oxygenated to do all the amazing things you are capable of. If you pause to listen you&amp;rsquo;ll hear the sound of wind, rhythmically blowing in and out of your lungs like clockwork; the original soundtrack to your life. Ideally you want that soundtrack to go on forever, we all do. However we want it, the events of last year have made it clear how much life our lives hinges on that soundtrack and how delicate it really is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/perspective/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time user of Future Me, a service that lets you send emails to the future. At the chosen date, when you least expect it, you will receive a letter detailing your worries, dreams and aspirations at this moment in time. I like these emails because they capture the not-so-picture-worthy moments that throw back photos can&amp;rsquo;t. A few days ago I received a letter I wrote 5 years ago and it gave me a lot to think about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Wrapped</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/new-year/</guid>
      <description>My, what a year! For the first time I&amp;rsquo;m looking back at a year ago and I feel &amp;hellip; different, some degree stronger, some degree wiser, a lot more focused, and ofcourse very different. While the global review of 2020 deserves a series of encyclopedias, this post is about my personal review.
Work&amp;nbsp;¶I switched to a new team at Microsoft in the first week of March; the very definition of bad timing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/bigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/bigger/</guid>
      <description>This has been one hell of a year, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not alone with this sentiment. Sometimes it feels like a horror movie where the plot thickens at every turn. Struggles we had before are that much magnified now that we have to experience it all from home without our usual distractions. Worse than that is how much death we&amp;rsquo;ve had to endure.
We&amp;rsquo;ve lost friends and family to Covid-19, we&amp;rsquo;ve lost our people to police brutality, we&amp;rsquo;ve lost our celebrities, heroes and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We could all use some hiit</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hiit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 21:00:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hiit/</guid>
      <description>Yes you spelled it right, not heat, HIIT! as in High Intensity Interval Training. By definition, HIIT is a form of training that involves cycles of short bursts on intense training followed by less intense recovery until fatigue/ exhaustion, in other words if you find yourself gasping for air throughout the workout, you are most likely HIITing. I don&amp;rsquo;t look forward to HIIT day but I love it, here is why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choices</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 09:14:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/choices/</guid>
      <description>Making big desicions takes significant time and effort, a good example: Career Planning. I started thinking about my career since the day I was able to form full sentences. It was inevitable considering &amp;ldquo;What do you want to be when you grow up?&amp;rdquo; was part of the script of conversing with adults. My responce to the question varied all the time from nun to teacher to musician, to poet to doctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Momentum</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/momentum/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Almost there&amp;rdquo;; sometimes these are the words of comfort I need to hear and sometimes they make want to attack the utterer. Being a runner and hiker means I get to hear them a lot more often than I want to. I love the intent behind them, they mean well. When I&amp;rsquo;m near the finish line, I welcome all variations of &amp;ldquo;Almost there&amp;rdquo; because its true, I can see the finish line and any form of discomfort I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing is bound to be over soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can run a marathon, you can do anything</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 07:02:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/marathon/</guid>
      <description>I came up with the title of this post when I was at the peak of runner&amp;rsquo;s high that is after running a full marathon last weekend. I&amp;rsquo;ll be grateful if it inspires you but this its a note to self when I&amp;rsquo;ll need the reminder. This is not the first time I ran a marathon but its the first time I felt good. Yes, you read that right, I felt good even while running up a heart attack hill, I felt good on mile 23, I felt good as I finished and I felt especially good when I was functional again in 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I run</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/why-i-run/</guid>
      <description>Every runner who is a also a writer writes their running story at some point. Its about time I wrote mine. I run at least 21 miles a week and have been consistently doing so for 4 years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t participate in every race there is, I&amp;rsquo;m far from a sub 2 hour half marathon, on many mornings its a struggle to get up and run. Despite all the struggles, I&amp;rsquo;m a consistent runner and sometimes a marathoner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 08:29:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://imaculate.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Over my relatively short career as a Software Engineer I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize the importance of documentation. No one uses a feature they haven&amp;rsquo;t heard or read about. Compared to hours spent reading and debugging code, documentation may sound trivial but it makes a big difference for customers as well as team knowledge sharing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve subconsiously known this for a while, its why I started amazife blog as a College Freshman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
